

Email: sunyu@caltech.edu
Homepage: sunyumark.github.io
Google Scholar: scholar.google.com/sun.yu

BIOGRAPHY

I am a **post-doctoral researcher** in the Department of Computing and Mathematical Sciences (**CMS**) at California Institute of Technology (**Caltech**). I am a member of Computational Cameras Group led by **Prof. Katie Bouman**. My research focuses on developing novel algorithms for intelligent, data-intensive, and fast computational imaging systems. My work has been applied to several real-world applications, including tomographic microscopy (TM), computed tomography (CT), and magnetic resonance imaging (MRI). I also work on theoretical analysis of my algorithms. I received my Ph.D. degree from Washington University in St. Louis (**WashU**) supervised by **Prof. Ulugbek S. Kamilov**.

Research Interests: Computational Imaging, Convex/Non-convex Optimization, Machine Learning.

EDUCATION

California Institute of Technology, Pasadena, CA Postdoctoral Fellow, Computing and Mathematical Sciences Department Advisor: <i>Prof. Katie Bouman</i>	Jul. 2022 – Present
Washington University in St. Louis, St. Louis, MO Ph.D. student in Computer Science Advisor: Prof. Ulugbek Kamilov	Jan. 2018 – May. 2022
Washington University in St. Louis, St. Louis, MO M.S. in Data Analytics & Statistics	Aug. 2015 – May. 2017
Sichuan University, Chengdu, China B.S. in Electronic and Information Engineering Advisor: <i>Prof. Qinggong Guo</i>	Sep. 2011 – Jun. 2015
WORKING EXPERIENCE	
Cedars Sinai Hospital, Los Angles, CA Clinical Data Research Specialist Mentor: Dr. David Ouyang	Aug. 2022 – Present
Nvidia, Santa Clara, CA Research Intern (Learning and Perception Research) Mentor: Dr. Orazio Gallo	May 2021 – Aug. 2021
Capacity, St. Louis, MO	May 2017 – Aug. 2017

AWARDS

Developer Intern

- · NeurIPS 2019 Travel Award
- Honor (top 15%), Department of Computer Science, Wash U, 2019-2021

PUBLICATIONS

Pre-print: ('*' indicates equal contribution)

[a 1.] R. Liu*, **Y. Sun***, J. Zhu, L. Tian, and U. S. Kamilov, "Zero-Shot Learning of Continuous 3D Refractive Index Maps from Discrete Intensity-Only Measurements." arXiv:2112.00002, **preprint**, 2021

Published: ('*' indicates equal contribution)

- [b 25.] W. Shangguan*, **Y. Sun***, W. Gan, and U. S. Kamilov, "Learning Cross-Video Neural Representations for High-Quality Frame Interpolation." European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2022. [Acceptance rate: 1492/5803 = 26%]
- [b 24.] W. Gan, Y. Sun, C. Eldeniz, J. Liu, H. An, and U. S. Kamilov, "Deformation-Compensated Learning for Image Reconstruction without Ground Truth," IEEE Trans. Med. Imag., in press.
- [b 23.] M. Xie*, J. Liu*, **Y. Sun**, B. Wohlberg, U. S. Kamilov "Joint Reconstruction and Calibration using Regularization by Denoising." Proc. IEEE Int. Conf. Comp. Vis. Workshops (ICCVW 2021), 2021
- [b 22.] **Y. Sun**, J. Liu, M. Xie, B. Wohlberg, and U. S. Kamilov, "CoIL: Coordinate-based Internal Learning for Tomographic Imaging." **IEEE Trans. Comput. Imag**, vol. 7, pp. 1400-1412, 2021
- [b 21.] J. Liu, **Y. Sun**, W. Gan, X. Xu, B. Wohlberg, and U. S. Kamilov, "SGD-Net: Efficient Model-Based Deep Learning with Theoretical Guarantees." **IEEE Trans. Comput. Imag.**, vol. 7, pp. 598-610, June 2021
- [b 20.] **Y. Sun***, Z. Wu*, X. Xu*, B. Wohlberg, and U. S. Kamilov, "Scalable Plug-and-Play ADMM with Convergence Guarantees. arXiv:1912.07087, **IEEE Trans. Comput. Imag.**, vol. 7, pp. 849-863, July 2021.
- [b 19.] J. Liu, **Y. Sun**, W. Gan, X. Xu, B. Wohlberg, and U. S. Kamilov, "Stochastic Deep Unfolding for Imaging Inverse Problems," Proc. IEEE Int. Conf. Acoustics, Speech and Signal Process (**ICASSP 2021**), Toronto, Canada, June 6-11, pp. 1395-1399.
- [b 18.] **Y. Sun**, J. Liu, Y. Sun, B. Wohlberg, and U. S. Kamilov, "Async-RED: A Provably Convergent Asynchronous Block Parallel Stochastic Method using Deep Denoising Priors." International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR 2021). [Spotlight: 114/2997 = 4%]
- [b 17.] W. Gan, Y. Sun, C. Eldeniz, H. An and U. S. Kamilov, "Deep Image Reconstruction using Unregistered Measurements without Groundtruth." Proc. Int. Symp. Biomedical Imaging 2021 (ISBI 2021), Nice, France, April 13-16, pp. 1531-1534.
- [b 16.] X. Xu, J. Liu, **Y. Sun**, B. Wohlberg, and U. S. Kamilov, "Boosting the Performance of Plug-and-Play Priors via Denoiser Scaling," Proc. 54th Asilomar Conf. Signals, Systems, & Computers (**ACSSC 2020**), Pacific Grove, CA, November 1–5, pp. 1305-1312.
- [b 15.] M. Torop, S. Kothapalli, Y. Sun, J. Liu, S. Kahali, D. A. Yablonskiy, and U. S. Kamilov, "Deep learning using a biophysical model for Robust and Accelerated Reconstruction (RoAR) of quantitative and artifact-free R2* images." Magn. Reson. Med., vol. 84, pp. 2932-2942, 2020.
- [b 14.] X. Xu, **Y. Sun**, J. Liu, B. Wohlberg, and U. S. Kamilov, "Provable Convergence of Plug-and-Play Priors with MMSE denoisers." **IEEE Signal Process. Lett.**, vol. 27, pp. 1280-1284, 2020.
- [b 13.] G. Song, **Y. Sun**, J. Liu, and U. S. Kamilov, "A New Recurrent Plug-and-Play Prior Based on the Multiple Self-Similarity Network." **IEEE Signal Process. Lett.**, vol. 27, pp. 451-455, 2020.
- [b 12.] J. Liu, **Y. Sun**, C. Eldeniz, W. Gan, H. An, and U. S. Kamilov, "RARE: Image Reconstruction using Deep Priors Learned without Ground Truth." **IEEE J. Sel. Topics Signal Process.**, vol. 14, no. 6, pp. 1088-1099, 2020.
- [b 11.] Z. Wu, **Y. Sun**, A. Matlock, J. Liu, L. Tian, and U. S. Kamilov, "SIMBA: Scalable Inversion in Optical Tomography using Deep Denoising Priors." **IEEE J. Sel. Topics Signal Process.**, vol. 14, no. 6, pp. 1163-1175, 2020.
- [b 10.] Y. Sun*, J. Liu*, and U. S. Kamilov, "Block Coordinate Regularization by Denoising," IEEE Trans. Comput. Imag., vol. 6, pp. 908-921, 2020.

- [b 9.] Z. Wu, **Y. Sun**, J. Liu, and U. S. Kamilov, "Online Regularization by Denoising with Application to Phase Retrival," Workshop on Learning for Computational Imaging, **ICCVW 2019**, pp. 3887-3895.
- [b 8.] J. Liu, **Y. Sun**, X. Xu, and U. S. Kamilov, "Image Restoration using Total Variation Regularized Deep Image Prior," Proc. IEEE Int. Conf. Acoustics, Speech and Signal Process. (**ICASSP 2019**), pp.7715-7719.
- [b 7.] J. Liu, Y. Sun, and U. S. Kamilov, "Infusing Learned Priors into Model-Based Multispectral Imaging," IEEE International Workshop on Computational Advances in Multi-Sensor Adaptive Processing (CAMSAP 2019).
- [b 6.] Y. Sun, J. Liu, and U. S. Kamilov, "Block Coordinate Regularization by Denoising," Proc. Ann. Conf. Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS 2019), pp. 382–392. [Acceptance rate: 1428/6743 = 21%]
- [b 5.] **Y. Sun**, B. Wohlberg, and U. S. Kamilov, "Plug-In Stochastic Gradient Method," Proc. International Biomedical and Astronomical Signal Processing Frontiers Workshop (**BASP 2019**), p.75.
- [b 4.] Y. Sun, S. Xu, Y. Li, L. Tian, B. Wohlberg, and U. S. Kamilov, "Regularized Fourier Ptychography using an Online Plug-and-Play Algorithm," Proc. IEEE Int. Conf. Acoustics, Speech and Signal Process. (ICASSP 2019), pp.7665-7669. [Oral]
- [b 3.] Y. Sun, B. Wohlberg, and U. S. Kamilov, "An Online Plug-and-Play Algorithm for Regularized Image Reconstruction." IEEE Trans. Comput. Imag., vol.5, no.3, pp.395-408, September 2019.
- [b 2.] Y. Sun and U. S. Kamilov, "Stability of Scattering Decoder For Nonlinear Diffractive Imaging," Proc. 4th International Traveling Workshop on Interactions between Sparse models and Technology (iTWIST 2018), p.31. [Oral]
- [b 1.] **Y. Sun**, Z. Xia, and U. S. Kamilov, "Efficient and accurate inversion of multiple scattering with deep learning," **Optics Express**, vol.26, no.11, pp.14678-14688, May 2018.

PRESENTATIONS & TALKS

- [c 9.] Invited speaker at CVPR CCD Workshop, June 2022.
- [c 8.] Invited talk at Stanford Computational Imaging Lab, Jan 2022.
- [c 7.] invited talk at Boston University Computational Imaging Systems Lab, Dec 2021.
- [c 6.] Invited talk on at CMU Image Science Lab, Dec 2021.
- [c 5.] Invited talk at Caltech Computational Cameras Group, Oct 2021
- [c 4.] "SIMBA: Scalable Inversion in Optical Tomography using Deep Denoising Priors." Virtual, ICIP 2021.
- [c 3.] "Async-RED: A Provably Convergent Asynchronous Block Parallel Stochastic Method using Deep Denoising Priors." Virtual, ICLR 2021.
- [c 2.] "Block-coordinate Regularization by Desnoising." Vancouver, Canada, Dec. 8-14, NeurIPS 2019.
- [c 1.] "Stability of Scattering Decoder for Nonlinear Diffractive Imaging" Marseille, France, Nov. 21-23, iTWIST 2018.

PROFESSIONAL SERVICES

- Professional societies: IEEE Signal Processing Society, Student Member (2018-present)
- Consultant Associate Editor: IEEE Open Journal of Signal Processing (2022-present).

- Journal Reviewer: OSA Optica, SIAM Journal on Imaging Sciences (SIIMS), IEEE Journal of Selected Topics in Signal Processing (JSTSP), IEEE Transaction on Computational Imaging (TCI), IEEE Transaction on Signal Processing (TSP), IEEE Transaction on Image Processing (TIP), Signal Processing (SP) Applied Mathematics and Computation (AMC), IEEE Signal Processing Letters (SPL), Digital Signal Process (DSP), SPIE Journal on Electronic Imaging (JEI).
- Conference Reviewer/PC: International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI), IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP).

TEACHING SERVICE

As Course Teaching Assistant:

- CSE 585T Sparse Model for Imaging, Wash U. 2018 Fall.
- ESE 415 Optimization, Wash U. 2018 Spring, 2019 Spring, 2020 Spring.
- CSE 427S Cloud Computing and Big Data Application, Wash U. 2016 Fall, 2017 Spring, 2017 Fall.

SUPERVISED STUDENTS

Past Students (Co-advised with Prof. Kamilov):

- Yuyang Hu (M.S. ESE, Co-supervised with Weijie Gan), Now Ph.D student at Wash U.
- Wentao Shangguan (M.S. CSE), Now Ph.D student at Boston U.
- Renhao Liu (B.S./M.S. CSE), Now at Google Inc.
- Mingyang Xie (B.S. CSE, 2021), Now Ph.D student at U. Maryland
- Yiran Sun (M.S., 2021), Now Ph.D student at Rice U.
- Weijie Gan (M.S. CSE, 2020), Now Ph.D. student at Wash U.
- Zihui Wu (B.S. CSE, 2020), Now Ph.D. student at Caltech
- Max Torop (M.S. CSE, 2020), Now Ph.D. student at Northeastern U.
- Shiqi Xu (M.S. ESE, 2019), Now Ph.D. student at Duke U.
- Jiaming Liu (M.S. ESE, 2018), Now Ph.D. student at Wash U.
- Zach Pewitt (M.S. ESE, 2018), Now at Boeing
- Josehp Han (M.S. ESE, 2018), Now at Deloitte
- Jialong Zhang (M.S. ESE, 2018), Now at Schlumberger
- Fangying Zhai (M.S. ESE, 2018)
- Chunyuan Li (M.S. CSE, 2018)